hello I'm your host David Barnard and
with me today Revenue cat CEO Jacob Eide
Our Guest today is Vince Mayfield
co-founder and CEO of talking parents an
app that helps divorced or separated
parents better manage communication and
share responsibilities on the podcast we
talk with Vince about the right way to
raise prices the painful lessons from
picking the wrong tools and why you
should respond to every single app
review Vince thank you so much for
joining us on the podcast today I can't
wait to chat oh I'm so honored to be
here I'm a long time listener of the
podcast so I'm a huge fan so it's
amazing that I get to sit here and be on
the cast with you awesome and Jacob
freshly shorn you look like a baby
without your three foot beer nobody
respects me now because I'm cleanly
shaming I look like I'm 13 but I'll take
it I'll take it it's nice to be back
everybody I'm the same person I today
somewhere on the street stop me I don't
even know and she was like oh you shaved
I was like who are you that's pretty
good it for those of you listening to
the audio podcast you'll have to check
out YouTube and see if the new and
improved Jacob yeah all right so Vince I
wanted to kick things off talking about
the story of talking parents and how you
went from a consultancy where you were
grinding for that next client and just
always doing work for other people
always billing hourly or project and the
way you told it to me when we were
chatting before the podcast is that you
wanted to make money while you slept and
it's pretty great that you went from a
consultancy where you were just grinding
for those next clients to a 10 million
dollar a year ARR business which it's
just incredible so start me off with
what was that motivation and how did you
start that process of going from an
agency to being a product company so my
business partner Louis Erickson we've
been best friends since middle school so
we've known each other a long time we
kind of decided we wanted to go off and
start doing custom software development
and so we developed this Professional
Services organization about your nine we
made Inc 5000 list and we kind of
realized that when you had a business
now we didn't have a hobby anymore and
that we really needed to think
differently we met this guy named
Stephen Nixon and Stephen had graduated
from law school and was a private
practice as an attorney he'd been a
prosecutor he'd been a defense attorney
and he was in this practice with his
brother and his brother was a family law
attorney so Stephen shows up into court
after his brother gets tapped to be a
magistrate and there's two co-parents
and they're going back and forth over
this record of communications which once
got text messages in one hand and
Facebook post and emails and they're
going back and forth and the judge is
annoyed and both attorneys are racking
up the hours and so the judge finally
throws it back and says okay you guys go
off on y'alls and you guys work this out
and then come back to me so Steven sort
of came up with this idea to build this
app so he hired him guy working out of
his house and I hadn't built it and then
got about a thousand people using it and
so he realized hey this is on service
inside of this guy's house and when I
call him he's not always responsive so
he starts to get worried because judges
are ordering people onto this software
and he's afraid that it's going to come
tumbling down or something so he stops
into the Bank of America building where
we're at and says hey I want you to take
a look at this app we go in and we look
at this app and we come back and we say
hey man this wasn't built to scale it's
kind of held together with bailing wire
and duct tape but we think the idea is
really cool what would you think about
us forming a whole new company and let's
rebuild this thing so that it will scale
and so we came together and started to
figure out how do we use the
Professional Services to mutually
support the app and then build the app
up and take it from there how did that
go transitioning from thinking like a
Hired Gun to now we've got this product
I think there's a lot of agencies out
there who try and make the jump but it
really is a different skill set how did
that part of the transition go for the
bit Wizards now talking parents crew
it's a difficult transition and I will
tell you for the first couple of years
we didn't have the app monetized as far
as a product we were thinking about you
know when you build custom software
you're just building things and getting
them done and you're pulling in pieces
and putting it together
it may or may not need to scale to the
level that this app did and so when
we've started bringing in third-party
components and stuff like that we really
hadn't thought through all the things in
the very beginning and that created some
technical debt and really got us to
start reworking things that we had
already done before as we were trying to
get that right product Market fit and I
think the other thing that was different
for us was we didn't understand really
who our customer was in the beginning
you're an agency you're used to having a
customer who tells you what to do you're
not as deep in the product you're not
having to think who's our customer it's
like well I mean you know who your
customer is the person who's short on
software development right that's
ultimately I mean your customer right
surely you need to align your goals with
theirs but even the best person who
wants to do the Best Buy everybody is
going to follow their like most direct
incentive which is very different I was
wondering like before you had this
opportunity land in your lap was this a
goal for you to bring in to like own
your own product product and this is
just an opportunity it just was like
right time right moment like let's do
this or had you tried to do this
transition was just like a strategic
thing or just something like
opportunistic when you're in a custom
software business everybody comes to you
and say hey I got an idea and we want
you to build it for us but we don't have
any money so you build it and we'll give
you a piece of it and we quickly learned
that our job was to be software
engineers and not figure out somebody's
business model or how they're going to
work but we did have a couple of things
that we had attempted one of them was a
product where we became the sole
reseller of it online we built the
website did the stuff but it was actual
physical product it had to be shipped it
was called Tailgater carrier and so we
did that for a couple of years we
invested and it didn't work out we had
to basically shut it down working with
another group of guys and we knew we
were just looking for that right thing
that seemed like it made the right fit
and that we could take and make money
while we were sleeping yeah I mean I
don't know the details but when it came
to you and it says like this thing's
getting out of control I can't handle
the demand that yeah that's our priority
product Market fit right at that point
right like people always ask like how do
I know I have product Market fit and
there's varying levels there's different
definitions of market right and how well
the fit is in there but you know that
moment when the product is growing
despite all the problems right that's
usually the definition that there's
something there so whether you
consciously knew it or not like that was
the right moment and it sounds like like
there was probably a natural limit to
where this would go without your
expertise right without some real
engineering I mean I think it's really
hard this Echoes against advice I've
gotten and heard from you know investors
in my world and stuff about it's just
really hard to own a product and build a
product without in-house engineering
without being somebody in the driver's
seat who's technical enough to drive the
product forward and this is a good
example of where somebody was short on
that expertise and probably would have
been Limited in how far they could take
it yeah and I think besides just the
product Market fit and understanding and
having somebody that could do the
software engineering and work right
there with you I think another side of
it was is that Lewis and I had already
taken a lot of risk our business had
been in business for 10 years at that
point now we're at 25 years for bit
Wizards and Stephen came from the law
Arena where they're all in the risk
mitigation business right and so you had
a couple of entrepreneurs and people
that understood that aspect of it what
it meant to take risks and we were able
to work work with Stephen and sort of
get him outside his comfort zone so that
we could scale this and make it go well
so it was really mutually beneficial we
really all fit together well but I will
tell you we thought we understood who
our customer was in the beginning but we
really didn't and so that's kind of a
good segue because we thought our
customer was the court system yeah good
luck selling SAS to the court system I
mean well at least you know where they
are yeah but if you go knocking on their
door they don't look kindly upon that I
guess it's probably also true well and
they also only want to talk to other
people in their profession you know it's
kind of like a lot of regulated
Industries they've got older technology
and things like that but we knew that
they were a Channel or an influencer so
initially we made the application free
and Steven thought we were going to
monetize through Google AdSense and so
we came to the conclusion pretty quickly
I said hey look everybody in that
courtroom is making money we've got to
make money to scale this thing so that
we can fuel it and build the features
and functions that the customers want
but our customer isn't the court system
so we changed and decided to monetize
based upon the apps and get a
subscription model going and when we did
that and put the focus in the customer
and the people that were actually giving
us money in fact I had a professor at
Notre Dame that told me he said
strategically you know who it is they're
the person that gives you money they're
the ones that are in the driver's seat
so it's amazing how we have to sometimes
we have to go learn these lessons from
fancy professors when it's like
absolutely it's like right in front of
you right so when you say customers
you're talking about the parents right
like the folks that are in a
co-parenting Arrangement that's
absolutely correct in those early days
when you introduce a subscription you
still did use a freemium model right so
tell me about your decision making
around okay this is never going to scale
big enough to make meaningful money on
ads we're going to use subscriptions but
we need some hook so how did you think
about freemium early and then I'd
actually want to go through the
different phases of your freemium
strategy as well well Steven thought
that the basic messaging part of what we
were doing was the core item and we were
already given that away for free through
the freemium model so we said you know
when we decided to monetize you got to
remember this is 0.9010 11 right and
apps are coming out and so we're like
okay so we're going to build some apps
and apps have notifications which you
didn't really have them very well over
the web so it started as a web app it
was it was like a full web experience
before okay exactly and so we said okay
so now we're going to give the mobile
apps and the incentive is going to be
well if you want to use mobile apps then
we're going to charge you for that on a
subscription basis and there was some
discussion that went back and forth
about whether we're going to charge a
one-time fee and what the price point
was I mean at that point in time it was
like the market was not really there for
charging consumer subscriptions on
mobile like I don't even think that
technically have any subscriptions on
the apps are told 11 or 12 until it was
everybody was able to use it yeah and so
we went through a lot of argument back
and forth about how to do that and then
when we finally did get it monetized and
get it on a subscription it was closer
to 2015 when we finally got that working
the way it needed to work so we probably
burned through close to a million
dollars revamping the app starting to
Market we were literally sending Stephen
out around the country on an airplane to
talk to judges and Clerks of Court and
stuff were you not monetizing at all
through that period no not really all we
were doing then we didn't really start
monetizing until the end of 2015
beginning in 2016 other than through the
Google AdSense Revenue oh so you did
have a little bit of that I mean
normally AdSense has a strategy or ads
as a strategy doesn't really work unless
you're mass mass Market but then I was
thinking like this kind of could be mass
mass market right like there's got to be
millions of people in this Arrangement
right that could potentially use a
co-parenting app yeah they weren't
necessarily divorced they couldn't had a
kid together and never been married it's
got to be a bigger Market than I mean
everybody could probably take more than
two hands to name people they know in
this situation right which is a larger
addressable Market than a lot of like a
lot of apps we talk to right so you had
that going for you I don't think it was
totally crazy but you guys were pouring
r d budget into this thing like were you
like pouring effort into the app for
those five years like as you were just
building that functionality was it kind
of on the back burner or like how are
you approaching it we first revamped the
web app and then we went in and started
doing the mobile apps on the latter part
after a lot of discussion and some of
the things that we did early on that
were really important we started asking
customers at least surveying them and
saying okay what do you want what would
you pay for what features or functions
do you like how can you know this be
better for you it was pretty rudimentary
nothing like what's available today it
was just simply a couple of software
engineers and a legal guy sitting in a
room saying okay well what kind of
questions we want to ask customers so we
started to get that survey data back and
figure out and solidify what we wanted
and when we released the first app I
personally felt like we were charging
too little for it which caused some
problems later on because as we started
to add more value and more functionality
and figure out how to build out our
tiers and give customers a compelling
reason to not only utilize the app but
stay on we had to deal with some of that
Legacy stuff that we were doing from
before when your app is free now you're
charging 4.99 and then later on you want
to charge them 9.99 and now we have two
tiers where it's 9.99 and 24.99 and so
how do you manage customer expectations
how do you deliver the value to them so
that they feel like that they're getting
something unique and that they're
willing to continue to pay for and stick
with you when the app had fewer features
and didn't have as big an audience and
product Market do you not think maybe it
wasn't right option to start at a lower
price so you're talking about tech debt
in that the price was lower and having
to transition to a higher price it's
kind of a combination of tech debt
because you have to manage the
subscriptions and like business debt of
like we used to be a different app now
we've added all these features but do
you think maybe that was actually a
better staging of the app to start low
and then move forward versus do you
think you could have gotten 25 a month
in those early days like is there regret
that you should have been charging 25
from the beginning do you think you
really could have done that I think we
could have monetized sooner I'd like to
tell you that what we did was genius and
it all worked out the way we wanted to
where you're supposed to that's what you
do when you're taking your Victory lap
that it was all clear the whole time
through your Genius but the reality is
is that we stumbled through it and we
just made mistakes and you know there
was a lot of argument and discussion and
back and forth and there were some lean
times where you know I had to tell
Stephen at one point I said hey I can't
continue to pay you a salary right now
times are lean and the Professional
Services realm so monetization has to be
a strategy and has to be something
important that we're doing and I would
say that from 09 to probably 15 although
we rebuilt the web app we dabbled and it
really wasn't until 15 that we got
things monetized and really started
getting them going and then we started
adding in more features and that type of
stuff it was stressful they got better
as we made money you know they say money
can solve problems when you're pulling
up by your bootstraps it does and the
smart use of that money and making the
right bets is what's important on the
point of starting low and going high
versus starting high and going low the
device I always give is start high
because like the worst case scenario is
nobody buys it right and then you're
giving people a discount right versus
the flip side is you give everybody some
price that's way under the True Value
you've now set the expectation that like
hey this is only worth 4.99 a month
which I would imagine is a fairly High
retention user base like yours like for
some apps that are Turn and Burn I use
the word churn and burn with love right
apps that maybe don't like focus on
super long-term retention like you can
more freely experiment with prices
because your customers are kind of
cycling in and out but for an app where
the expectation might be that somebody
uses you for 18 years right or some
really long period of time setting that
expectation matters right because you're
going to have that customer relationship
for a while so yeah normally I'm like oh
just respect your existing users but
feel free to mess around but in a case
where you might have a longer term base
like you might want to be more careful I
just find it's always easier to make
things cheaper like nobody gets mad at
you right you're gonna have the same
amount of tech debt and business debt by
like reducing a price you're going to
lose money potentially from existing
users if you bring them down but like at
least the emotional labor is less right
you're like lowering the price and
you're still trying to find that Optimum
right you're still solving the same
problem you're just coming from a
different starting point on the curve
but when you have like really deep
product Market fit and you've built out
all those features then you do actually
have very few people who complain when
you raise the price and that's the next
part of the story I wanted to get to is
that you did end up raising the price on
all of your existing subscribers tell me
about how you planned that and then how
did it go again at the beginning we
didn't have a lot of instrumentation and
we weren't really sure to Jacob's point
the people that are with us are
predominantly court ordered so raising
prices when it's already low is tricky
because they're already mad because
they're typically in a co-parenting
relationship not all but some of them
are so it's a very delicate matter to
raise prices and go forward we were
actually surprised we said okay well if
we lose half of our customers as we
raise the price from 499 to 9.99 what is
that going to do to our Revenue what's
going to happen and I've been to some
pricing seminars and stuff like that and
talked to some different people and I
said there's no way that's going to
happen right so we just sort of planned
that we would lose at least half and
what we're presently surprised is that
we got a few complaints but actually
people understood that when we rolled it
out we added additional value so when we
first rolled it out our 9.99 plan we
added in what we call call accountable
calling which allowed people to be able
to make phone calls and have it be
transcribed and made a part of the
record so it was more than just the
messaging that was going back and forth
over or keying it in and so every time
we've raised prices or every time we've
busted out to tears we've made sure that
we've bundled that with a group of value
that somebody would get that the
customers had asked for from us
surveying them so we could say hey look
yes we're raising prices but we're
bringing you new features and functions
that you asked us for and we're
listening to what you're having to say
and we're making sure that it's a value
to you so turns out we maybe lost a
quarter or so and maybe some of that was
transitional while they were mad and
then they came back because some of them
and I would probably venture to say it's
probably about a 60 40 split but 60
percent are court ordered about 40
percent or not but we always offered a
free version if you wanted to use the
web version you could get it for free so
he said okay if you don't want to pay
for the extra features here you can
always go back to the free version and
you can use it and that satisfies court
orders in most cases yes sir that's a
huge lesson right there though that I
think a lot of subscription apps now
that you can more easily raise prices
are not heating if you're Netflix yeah
you can like increase the price 25 just
because your Netflix and people are
going to stay subscribed but bundling
any price raise with like clear
additional value I think was
a good product marketing right it's like
you probably already shipped a lot of
apps yeah I know prices and not do it I
mean it goes back to um you know
something we've been thinking about our
Revenue got a lot of recently it's just
like negotiation tactics and like as
we're closing deals like how do we
create non-controversial interactions
with customers as we're trying to like
come to a partnership agreement and
there's certain ways you can present you
know it's pricing it's all pricing right
it's like presentation of pricing it's
so psychological already you have as an
app developer a lot of surface area to
influence that psychological experience
variants if you say like increased price
you know an increase price with an
increase in delivered value is not
actually a net loss for people right
they can opt out on a liquidity basis
like that Surplus value for me I do not
need right and they can choose to opt
out but you know in most cases you know
if you're surveying users and what you
think of is good then what you're
building is hitting their needs so it's
not going to be the case right when were
y'all doing this I guess was it recently
so we've made some additional changes
when we went to the 24.99 tier that
happened at the end of
2022 Okay so we've now been doing it
right about a year and about six months
or so but that's a second tier right so
you have the 9.99 tier so you doubled
the price from 499 to 9.99 but now you
have the option in the app to get the
999 tier or the 24.99 tier correct
that's correct can you talk a little bit
about like what did you bundle into that
like what are you targeting with that
tier so the way the free tier worked is
that we have the record and so when you
want to go to Court then you buy a copy
of the record from us we will either
give you a digital copy or you can
download it as a PDF which a lot of
Courts won't take and then the other
option is to do a printed copy so we
would actually print them out bind them
do an affidavit and then ship them to
them when we went to the 999 tier from
the 499 tier we basically structured it
so that you got a Deeper Discount on
plated records because printed records
cost us a significant amount of Labor
and effort to go and do it but then we
also added in calling and then when we
went to our 24.99 tier we added in video
calling and it's not just calling there
you got to keep in mind that what we're
doing is we're recording the call we're
transcribing it we're making it a part
of the record we're breaking apart the
channel so that you can see all them and
then it's put in a format that if you do
go to court the court can actually see
how it's all broken down by dates and
conversations so what somebody said if
you call your spouse out or former
spouse out in there and say something
ugly well the Court's going to see that
right so the idea is that it's
reinforcing people to be civil and so we
carefully picked each one of those items
so video calling is expensive for us
because you know you've got to store
that video and you've got to store that
audio so we made it so that they got a
bundle of minutes and a bundle of time
that made really sense and then we could
take it up each level as we went forward
so that was the primary again it was
like adding and creating value right and
then pricing that value actually
capturing that created value which is
you know five times what your original
price point was right now for that new
service but depending on the situation
that you're in if you think about a tool
that's going to allow you you know if
you're in a contentious co-parenting
situation or whatever allow you that
freedom to video communicate makes a lot
of sense and so how has that been is I
finally having multiple we have multiple
pricing tiers here and like old ones and
new ones and I find I need to be like
super hard to like wrap my head around
how did adding tearing make your lives
Better or Worse potentially more
complicated I don't know that it made it
more complicated I think what it
organized our customers around people
that understood what we were doing and
got the value and were willing to pay
the higher price point to it so we cater
to all the customers but we added other
features in too I didn't mention this
one but we actually have accountable
payments so they can make payments for
child support or alimony and it's all
tracked and it's all part of the system
and you're at the 999 we charge less for
that because there is some per
transaction charges for us and then we
charge even less when you're at the
24.99 tier so I don't know that it
created a big problem for us I think the
bigger problem for us was trying to
extricate the old 499 customers and get
them up to the new level it's like you
always said it's harder to charge people
more money than it is to reduce the cost
right yeah I mean 20 Gap is massive
right for that five dollar user if
you're staring and being like well I get
this for five it may not be five times
the value right but it still might be
worth it if that makes sense to them
yeah and interestingly what we found out
was is that most of our Apple users were
on the higher tier you know if you think
about it you pay a thousand or almost
two grand now for an iPhone with all the
stuff on it we found that we had more
customers over in that room and we could
see where certain customers were more
price conscious Vince when you're
talking about the pricing in 25 a month
on the premium tier and like how much
value you're having to deliver it's just
reminding me how much opportunity there
still is for subscription apps to
deliver a ton of value and charge for
that value I think of speechify the
Texas speech app they charge 120 a year
I mean a couple years back I was like
holy crap that's really expensive but it
delivers a ton of value and for those of
you listening to to the podcast there's
a lot of nuances in talking parents
business it's not going to apply to your
specific business but you should be
looking for these opportunities to layer
on deeper and deeper value because there
is still so much opportunity to increase
the value you're delivering and then
actually charge for it because 25 bucks
a month for a consumer subscription app
but you're delivering that kind of value
you're delivering sophisticated video
audio transcriptions all that kind of
stuff it's for affidavits I want one
thing I wanted to ask you Vince so like
if one parent has a subscription does
the other one get access to features or
is it all for like one side of the match
it's one side but it gets the other
parent a reason or incentive to maybe
want to go to the next level so if
they're at the 999 tier they'll get
calling but they have to be at the 24.99
tier if they want to get videos so one
parent may have video and the other one
may not or maybe they want to have a
video chat with their kid where the
other parent doesn't necessarily have
that capability we're trying to
reinforce where that value is and get
them to move up the chain there and
subscribe at that particular level but
if they can't afford it and it's not at
their level they can get the features at
the level there so even at the Free
level you know there's ways for a
premium person to talk to somebody at
the Free level and some of the things
that we're talking about doing is
figuring out a way to let one co-parent
pay for the other co-parent which is
complicated it is because your land yeah
yeah because some people think that well
first of all the parents don't want to
be controlled by the other co-parent
right so there's some nuances about what
we have to do to help navigate this but
I want to make one point about what
David was talking about with value and
that's that you know one of the things
that we found about people is that they
like to compartmentalize elements of
their life and they don't want to have a
million apps right and so co-parenting
is a very important aspect you're
shepherding young lives between two
people and you're trying to keep it
harmonious and keep yourself out of
court the value that talking parents
brings there is its accountability
across all those communication mediums
into a record that can be utilized in
court and so at each level the parents
can pick and choose the features of the
values that matter the most to them
and then that they're willing to pay for
in order to help them manage this like I
said we noticed that some of our Less
Price conscious customers typically on
Apple you got two co-parents one on each
side pan 24.99 for it but I would also
say it also costs us a lot of money to
deliver that right there's consumables
there that I have to pay for in my unit
and in my economic cost and so it's
priced in a way that allows us to
deliver that premium experience for them
at a price point that they're willing to
pay for and that I can cover the costs
and still make money you're talking
about nudging those parents who aren't
paying to pay and now you need both
parents involved and I imagine there's a
lot to understanding the usage of the
app how do you instrument that how do
you figure out what your customers need
so initially I told you we did it it's
pretty rudimentary we did surveying and
Survey Monkey and that type of thing
there was a lot of discussion about what
we thought and we kept telling ourselves
and especially when I hired my my new
director of marketing Heather Ruiz she
came in from the business to Consumer
field and you know that's different
obviously from B to B it's a different
mindset in a different way that you
market and she really solidified that we
had to get back some instrumentation and
really truly instrument the app and
understand the customer Journey not over
instrument it but basically have the
things that so we understood what that
was we started with adjust but the
problem with the justice is that it's
centered around that app download and
for us that isn't a conversion point
from us they can download the app but
it's not effective until they match with
a co-parent and they're talking we put
Firebase in place and then we started
looking at and sort of did a fly-off to
see what do we need for a platform and
we looked around and we saw that
everybody's using segment right we kept
hearing segment over and over again and
when my software Engineers looked at it
they're like hooray it's a giant
database it stores a bunch of stuff in
it and we can aggregate it and make it
anything we want and my marketers went
time out we don't want to be building
uis and having to integrate with Tableau
or power bi or something like that we
need a more accurate picture across all
the platforms so we ended up boiling it
down between segment and a product
called Bloom reach Bloom reach is a
customer data platform which is a little
bit different because we're having these
problems that are happening right now
with privacy and with third party and so
this allows us to have basically first
party data we believe that first party
date is King it allows us to map what's
going on with the people that come to
our website and then track our customers
as they go through that Journey so we
did all that instrumentation in the last
two years and it's really paying
dividends and helping us understand how
our customers think and what they do and
in addition to that we've also created
sort of a community where we're giving
back something more than just the app so
some of the things that we're doing is
like our coffee and co-parenting and
we're bringing in F experts like Dr
ramadi or Mark Pearson who's a renowned
negotiator and counselor and an
influencer like Caroline Kelly and
brought them in to provide that value to
our customers through our coffee and
co-parenting so that they felt like they
were getting their video series or was
coffee and co-parenting so coffee and
co-parenting is like webinars that we
offer periodically and then we bring
these experts in and provide that
they'll take over our social media or
take over the blogs and bring stuff in
and interact with the customers and you
were mentioning that in relation to
bloom reach is that something you're
actually tracking In Bloom reach to
understand kind of the impact of that
community-based marketing basically
absolutely so it's tied into our social
media it's tied into all of our
advertising so all somebody has to do is
come to our site once or one of our
landing pages and then we can track
their history and what they're doing
over time and then we know when they
convert and what that Journey looks like
for them deciding on Bloom rich and
doing a bake off it can be a challenging
Prospect with engineering battling with
marketing battling with the business
team and got pricing and who's going to
lead and all that kind of stuff how has
that gone as you've evolved the tooling
like going from one tool to another and
figuring out like what's actually going
to work best for your business we've
made some mistakes as we've gone through
this being software engineers and you
know having an attorney as part of the
company being a little more risk adverse
on things you know we always looked at
what was the cheapest and what was the
easiest to integrate right from a
software engineering perspective and
cost there's a couple instances where
that kind of burned us and so one of the
is that we have an audio translation
service and the company that we use now
is called assembly AI but we had a
previous one that was a startup company
and we didn't pay particular attention
to the unit economics there and we
didn't pay particular their attention to
how it might scale
and so what ended up happening is is
that we started having problems with
transcription and we started having
disconnections from their service and we
had to go back and we found that cheaper
isn't always better right so we actually
made this transition to assembly we cut
our cost in half and we got more
features and functionality out of it
because instead of they would charge us
for each channel that we were
transcribing whereas under the new
system it charged us under dual Channel
and allowed us to go through so the
learning from that is to make sure that
you understand clearly what the unit
economics are what it's going to do to
your cost of goods sold and to make sure
that you're not you know from a software
SharePoint sounds cool that we're going
to hook up with another startup company
but if they can't scale when you're
scaling you've just added a problem to
your scaling and we've had to go back
and re-engineer as a result of that and
it's happened in more than one occasion
I have to imagine on all the train I
mean this assembly AI sounds like it's
probably new I'd imagine the costs are
going to come down on transcription and
stuff right now because there's just so
much Innovation and AI audio video stuff
right now there is plus it handles
multi-language which is another feature
and function that we want to put in but
I have to put some props in there you
know Revenue cap was the first tooling
that we integrated to basically help us
manage our subscriptions we tried to
build that ourself and it was a huge
mistake it was a debacle we were running
around chasing our tail every time Apple
would change something or every time
Google would change something it was
just a night now we chase our tails for
you that's how it works except and the
price doesn't go up when that happens so
that's the benefit it's de-risked
exactly well I mean you scale with us as
we scale and so that's what I'm talking
about paying attention to how that works
and that was the first and then I
mentioned assembly I The Other Woman
swim we had another startup that we
worked with to help us with our video
right when we're doing our calling it
was our Flagship feature we
underestimate a little bit what the cost
was going to be to store the video over
the Long Haul we have some unique things
with the co-parents that we want to mask
location and that type of thing and mask
the phone numbers and you know we have
issues of trying to mux all that
together and so we want this other
company and they were great they're
really nice but we started having
problems with our Flagship feature and
we had compared them to twilio
and we decided we're going to go back
with this new startup and we're going to
help them out we're going to work with
us and go forward but the reality is
they couldn't scale with us and so we
ended up making the transition to twilio
and the advantage there is now I've got
a Global Network at scale that I can
actually integrate in with so I would
tell other Founders if you're a software
engineer by trade you know your tendency
is I want to build it myself and the
answer is don't try to build it yourself
you find It Best in Class don't chance
on the money and make sure you pay
particular attention to the unit
economics the other thing that I would
say that it's really important is I tell
my Engineers all the time why are you
spinning your heels on that call Revenue
cat or call twilio right this is why we
pay for support right these are the guys
are the experts in their product let's
utilize that and I don't mind paying
some extra money to be able to have that
because if I do that then my Engineers
are off developing new features or
functions for my you know customers that
have a higher Roi I think this is
something that I'm glad it sounds like
you guys have made that transition I see
a lot of companies that are I don't want
to describe it they're somewhat dogmatic
about it right about never taking things
from the outside and there's legal
reasons right there's risks where you
just identified there but like folks
always like ignore they over index on
the risk of the startup that goes out of
business which can be mitigated right
with a couple easy checks like I'll say
this for folks evaluating Revenue cat or
any tool if the company's not public if
they're public you can just look at
their financial position right you can
see how much cash they have you can kind
of understand their insolvency if
they're private if it's a startup ask
and if the salesperson will tell you say
like let me talk to your founder I want
to know which like how much money you
guys have we do fewer of those
conversations now but in the early days
I was like had to get on a lot of phone
calls and be like listen I only have
seven hundred thousand dollars in the
bank but here's my plan right like we're
we're settled like if I had to you know
we needed to lean back we'd be
profitable like the businesses you know
it which was hasn't always been the case
for a lot of deaf tools right it's
really good to hear that you know you've
opened up to that because like I think a
lot of people do themselves a disservice
like the whole economy and since the
Middle Ages is based on they're not even
pre-middle ages since basically The
Agrarian revolution has been based on
specialization right and we've entered
this period where with software it can
happen at like a different way right
like specialized crafts people can be
trading information in real time and
then metering and exchanging that and
that's kind of what's caused the
explosion and value creation that we've
seen over the last two thousand or ten
thousand years so to deny that and be
like oh we're going to build everything
in-house like deny is something that's
been working really well again
conditioned on the risks right
conditioned on doing what's right for
your business and and then also you
learn how to do good vendor integration
right where you're defending yourself a
little bit you're being like yeah we're
gonna put this in we're going to isolate
it a little bit so that we have that
optionality if this vendor doesn't work
out for us we can easily switch over to
another or we can bring it in-house if
we have to and stuff like that your r d
dollars should be going into ipe which
beats the market right which is creating
extra margin and extra value for your
customers because like just solving the
base needs of the business probably
isn't going to bring a big return for
that dollars absolutely and I have a lot
of scars to prove that it took me a long
time to learn that
one of the frustrating things though
about the subscription app industry
specifically you said you should just go
with Best in Class tooling but so many
of the best in class toolings that I
would generally recommend to you know
folks just starting out you got to start
off with like a thirty fifty thousand
dollar a year Enterprise plan to even
start integrating the tool and I wish
some of these bigger kind of Best in
Class companies like iterable Embrace on
the customer journey and customer data
platform side and even some of the
bigger like mmps and other things like
that I wish there were more companies
open to that kind of let us start with
you and grow with you instead of like
you can't even implement the solution I
never I did
like don't tell me
because I do it out of a moral
imperative right I have to believe that
long term it will net out right but a
lot of these companies they just because
typically those 50k and up those
Enterprise contracts like you can build
a go to market motion around that and
it's typically pretty efficient and
relatively easy to grow compared to like
a Bottoms Up motion might take forever
and be very costly yeah and twilio is a
good example of like there are still
tools out there that charge on unit
economics that can work if you're
delivering value and making it you know
you scale with them you don't have to
sign a sixty thousand dollar plan just
to get started but yeah I wish everybody
could just start with Best in Class
tools so it's a trade-off Mission really
early on you can't always start with
best-in-class tools but it's cool to
hear that you're actually still using
Firebase because that's something a lot
of folks start out with and then
eventually move on to a mixed panel an
amplitude a segment or something like
that but at least there are tools like
Firebase where maybe the best in class
at everything but they're good enough to
take talking parents to 10 million in AR
absolutely I think the key thing there
for those that can't necessarily get the
best in class in the beginning because
because she just can't afford to do it
it's just follow good software
engineering techniques in a way that you
can actually pull stuff out as you go
because the app you are when you're in
your first year versus your second or
third year you're going to iterate
several times if I had a dollar for
every time we changed around technology
or kind of did something and I think
that was the benefit of us going back
and re-engineering it in the first place
was it allowed us to do that quicker I'm
not saying it's not problematic it is
there's certain paradigms that we
haven't been able to pull out but we
were able to integrate certain things in
and then switch them out because we
designed them properly so that if we had
to go from one transcription service to
another we could if we went from one
video provider to another we could and
what some Founders do is they get in a
big hurry it's hurry up and get it to
Market as quickly as I can which I
understand but at our point we kind of
already knew that we had a market and a
fit and I think as we were going through
we were making sure that what we could
do would scale and that we could change
things out as we moved along we do need
to start wrapping up but I want to do a
quick lightning round because I think
you have some really insightful points
here with talking parents I know
customer service is super important and
I don't think enough apps take that
super seriously so give us the 90 second
why do you care about support and then
how does that actually translate into
how you run your business and how your
customers respond well I'll say first
and foremost that I think that every
experience that somebody has with your
brand sets a mental image of who you are
in it and so you know if I'm going to
charge a premium price then they need to
have premium support right one of the
things that we've done that I think is
absolutely important to us and we didn't
do it in the beginning and we've only
been doing it in the last year and a
half is that on app reviews we go in and
reply to every app review with a human
response right even if somebody's just
complaining just to complain or they're
complaining about their co-parent
relationship or something has nothing to
do with the app but I want my people I I
have my marketing team meets once a week
with my customer experience team and
they respond to all of those
and you know obviously Google gives us
less characters than say apple does but
people then feel like they're heard and
you're not writing it to answer just
that person you're writing it for
everybody that comes behind it and if
you've got a thoughtful reasonable
answer that empathizes with that
particular person then there's more of a
chance that they're going to come back
and they're going to think highly of
your app and I would say we do the same
thing with our app it's email support
only right now but one of the things
that we're thinking about doing for our
higher tiers is giving a phone support
and if we do that we'll add that in and
treat it with the same care so our thing
is about radical focus on the customer
because again as I said before they're
the ones that are paying us for the
service and so if they feel like they're
heard and that we're listening to them
they're going to continue to stay on
subscription with this or we're gonna
have great retention rates it's amazing
David is the whole point of this whole
project people making software that
helps people and then paying for it it's
the dream that's all we want right it
goes back to the you know their
customers who pays you it's true right
and reflecting on you just had Vince
about our own support we provide email
support to anybody just signed up you'll
never make us a dollar all the way up to
our biggest customers obviously there's
some gradations there and we kind of
like adjust resourcing depending but we
always want to get back to people within
a few hours no matter if they're just
lost and trying to figure out how to do
it and the reason being is because it
goes back to what you said it builds
that brand right it's like we're
establishing a relationship with a
community of users and how you react to
them and how you're able to treat them
whether it's visible or not or whatever
they'll tell their friends really
matters and really compounds especially
when you're serving like you guys a
somewhat Niche Community you have to
maintain that like people have to have a
high NPS of talking parents if you want
your business to take off in a community
where people are probably exchanging
information a lot so it's why I don't
look at the unit economics I don't want
to know right like
yeah you were talking earlier events
about making sure on tool you know the
unique economics and again I think too
many apps sleep on how important
customer success can be to building a
great app Business and so I think it's
really great that's a huge Focus for
talking parents and even if it is a
quote unquote money loser in the like
hour by hour unit economics it's not a
money loser in the long run so it's
really cool that you're focused on that
yeah I consider it table Stakes if
you're a good business yeah it's a cost
of doing business and when we hire
people we try to look for people that
have a lot of empathy because it's a
tough job right yeah
we complain about you know iOS
developers sometimes being cantankerous
and whatnot I can't imagine like people
already potentially where they're coming
from why they ended up in that app and
then they're having a frustrating moment
like I I've got to imagine your customer
experience team it has to be a very
special kind of person yeah and I think
there's an altruistic nature to all of
us here because a lot of the people in
the company are co-parents and so they
understand what it's like to be in that
environment we want to make co-parenting
better we want to make people's lives
better there's an altruistic notion to
this I mean obviously we want to make
money we got to do that to stay in
business but we also believe that our
app is delivering value that makes
people's lives better yeah and
ultimately you know helping kids right
in a potentially tough situation you
make me want to wear you guys any jobs
open
kind of excited it's a good Mission yeah
speaking of that actually do you have
any jobs open we need to wrap and if
there's anything else you want to share
as we wrap up well we're always hiring I
have a thing that I'll always be hiring
looking for good talent good people so I
would love for people to come check us
out at talkingparents.com and we try to
find a spot for good folks if we can
make it work and from the economic
standpoint awesome well Vince thanks so
much for joining us this fascinating
conversation fascinating business I got
to talk to you for like an hour and a
half before the podcast and just such a
fascinating business and really great
all the insights that you shared today
so thank you thank you and I appreciate
both of you having me on today I'm
honored thank you Jacob thank you David
thanks so much for listening
if you have a minute please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player
you can also stop by chat.sub club.com
to join our private community
foreign